In 2019, the most precious natural resource... is us.
Daybreakers is a action, fantasy, science fiction
film directed by Michael Spierig.
In the year 2019, a plague has transformed almost every human into a vampire.
Faced with a dwindling blood supply, the fractured dominant race plots their survival;
meanwhile, a researcher works with a covert band of vampires on a way to save humankind.
Edward Dalton, played by Ethan Hawke.
Charles Bromley, played by Sam Neill.
Lionel 'Elvis' Cormac, played by Willem Dafoe.
Audrey Bennett, played by Claudia Karvan.
Alison Bromley, played by Isabel Lucas.
Christopher Caruso, played by Vince Colosimo.
Daybreakers is a 2009 dystopian sci-fi action-horror vampire film
written and directed by Michael and Peter Spierig.
The film takes place in a futuristic world overrun by vampires, and centers around a vampiric corporation which
sets out to capture and farm the remaining humans while researching a substitute for human blood.
Ethan Hawke plays vampire hematologist Edward Dalton, whose work is interrupted by human survivors led by
former vampire 'Elvis' (Willem Dafoe), who has a cure that can save the human species.
An international co-production between the United States and Australia,
Daybreakers premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival in 2009.
It was released in the United Kingdom on 6 January 2010
and in North America on 8 January 2010.
The film grossed over $50 million worldwide (from a $20 million
budget) and received mixed-to-positive critical reception.
The film explores themes of experiment, sunrise, waitress, vampire, dystopia.
The tone is uplifting and dark and thought_provoking.